# DHRUV AKSHAY PANDIT

# DATA ANALYST

Lisbon, Portugal

dhruv.pandit2001@outlook.com

## ABOUT ME

Master's student in Applied Econometrics, having graduated with a BSc in Natural Sciences with a specialization in Mathematics. Proficient quantitative and qualitative data analyst with developed statistical and mathematical skills. Resourceful and driven, and does not have difficulty in grasping new concepts. Interested in the development, search and implementation of new solutions. My fields of interest are data analytics, business analytics, statistics, and econometrics.

## SKILLS

Python Excel Java

Power BI SQL WordPress

## **EDUCATION**

MSc Applied Econometrics & Data Forecasting

Lisbon School Of Economics & Management 2022-2024

BSc Natural Science (Specal. Mathematics)
Maastricht University

2019-2022

## **WORK EXPERIENCES**

## Operations Data Analyst at Stellantis India

Maastricht

Feb. 2022 - Jun. 2022

A 5 month internship for my bachelors thesis titled 'Improved order picking and storage strategies in automotive parts warehousing' in collaboration with Stellantis India. Skills utilised in this internship were qualitative research, data visualization and analysis, quantitative research, statistical analysis, Python (programming language), Pandas (software), Numpy and advanced exploratory data analysis.

## Key Accomplishments:

- Improved the lines-per-hour KPI of the main parts distribution centre for JEEP, FIAT and CITREON in India by 116%
- Recommendations to further improve operations efficiency were not capital intensive leading to positive client satisfaction
- Analysis of warehouse operations successfully identified areas of operations with significant impact on efficiency

## Lead Website Designer at Maastricht Gaels

Maastricht

Jul. 2021 - Present

## Key Responsibilities:

- Day-to-day management and updating of the website; ensure working status of the website
- · Handle the colour, composition, typography, and branding for the club

## Key Accomplishments:

- · Designed and solely set up custom website; implemented multipage, multi tab design
- Produced high client satisfaction, reaching 1.97k impressions for the website
- Encoded web shop for the club's merchandise

Aug. 2021 - Jun. 2022

## INTERNSHIPS

#### Head of Public Relatons at Maatricht Gaels

Maastricht

Sep. 2021 - Sep. 2022

### Key Responsibilities:

· Lead Social Media Manager for Instagram, LinkedIn, Website Blog, and Twitter

#### Key Accomplishments:

- Reached 1024% more new Instagram accounts than in the year prior
- Grew followers by 10.2% and increased profile visits
- Increased content interaction by 323% and engaged with 2700% more non-followers

### Finance Manager at Precious Plastic Maastricht

Maastricht

May. 2021 - Feb. 2022

### Key Responsibilities:

- Reviewed the organization's budget, managed accounting of the organization and oversaw bank transfers
- Coordinated day-to-day activities of the finance team
- Worked alongside the business team to explore new strategies to increase revenue

#### Key Accomplishments:

- Updated, sanitized, and set up accounting system for the organization
- Oversaw and managed the submission and consequent approval of grants totaling 10,000 euros to scale the organizational workforce and production capabilities

# NOTABLE COURSES

Statistics Optimization Databases Programming

Linear Algebra Differential Equations Multivariable Calculus Big Data

# LANGUAGES

English Native Speaker Hindi A2
German A2 Marathi A2

## HOBBIES

Gym, Gaelic Games, Cooking, Video Editing, Bass Guitar